PEARL CHRISTIAN

FRONT-END DEVELOPER & **FACILITATOR**

CONTACT INFO

- Nigeria
- +234 8152 583 776
- pearlchristian6@gmail.com
- pearly-c.github.io/portfolio
- linkedin.com/in/pearl-christian
- github.com/Pearly-c

EDUCATION

2019-2019

NIIT

Benin City, Edo Sate

Diploma: Web Development

2012-2016

Ota,Ogun Sate

Bells University of Technology

Bachelor of Science: Industrial Chemistry

SOFT SKILLS

Good communication problem-solving

Team-work

Creativity

Willingness to learn

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An ambitious, problem-solving front-end web developer with a high level of experience working on multiple projects. Self-motivated, passionate and hardworking with a penchant for meeting deadlines.

Interested in a role with a well-established organization that appreciates dedication and hardwork. Available to work remotely.

WORK HISTORY

08/2021 - CURRENT EMPOWER HER COMMUNITY

ENGINEERING LEAD

- Collaborate with team members to identify and fix technical problems.
- Delegate tasks/assignments to team members.
- Generate monthly status reports that clearly reflects all accomplishments in a given month.

02/2021 - CURRENT

MIDTOWN TECH HUB

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

- Build reusable code for future use, while striking a balance between functional and aesthetic design.
- Ensure web design is optimized for smartphones.
- Ensure brand consistency is maintained throughout design, while optimizing web pages for maximum speed and scalability.
- Perform detailed code review to improve code quality.
- Participate in training beginners in front-end web development.

05/2020 - 11/2020

SIGHT INNOVATION

WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

- Develop ideas for new programs by monitoring industry trends.
- Evaluate code to ensure it's properly structured, meets industry standards and compatible with browsers and devices.
- Participate in training beginners in back-end web development.

01/2017 - 11/2017

MATTHIAS ACADEMY

TUTOR

- Prepare Lecture notes.
- Conduct assigned classes at the scheduled time.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Javascript

ReactJS

Git version control/Github

Responsive web design

Web performance optimization

HTML/CSS/Bootstrap